wikivorce.com 2013-05-16

# Data Privacy Policy | UK Divorce Support Community

## What information do we collect and why?

You can access the Wikivorce website and browse certain areas without disclosing any personal information about yourself. 

Registering on our site is optional. If you choose not to register or provide personal information, you can still use the majority of the website. 

When you register you will be asked to submit personal information about yourself (e.g. name and email address etc.). 

By entering your details in the fields requested, you enable us to provide you with the services you select. Whenever you provide such personal information, we will treat that information in accordance with this policy. 

You can unregister or unsubscribe from email communications at any time by sending an email with 'unregister' or 'unsubscibe' in the title to [customersupport@wikivorce.com](mailto:customersupport@wikivorce.com). 

## How do we protect your personal details?

We have procedures governing the storage and disclosure of personal details to prevent unauthorised access and misuse. In addition, your personal information is password-protected: only you and Wikivorce have access to your personal information. 

For clarity the personal information which is password protected and covered by this privacy policy includes:  
\- your email address  
\- your name  
\- your private messages/emails 

However, please be aware that other (possibly personal) information that you voluntarily choose to publish on the site will be viewable by guests and members. This includes information that you submit through:  
\- the forum  
\- your blog  
\- in the chatroom  
\- in a comment

Wikivorce will not accept any liability for the consequences of this information that you chose to publish being accessed and used by a third party. 

## Access to your personal information

You have the right to request a copy of the personal information Wikivorce holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. (Please note that we charge £5 for information requests.) Please address requests via email to [customersupport@wikivorce.com](mailto:customersupport@wikivorce.com). However, you may find it easier to just login and view your profile on the website where you can view and update all your personal information. 

## How do we use your personal information?

Wikivorce may disclose and use personal information collected about you within its own organisation for the purpose of internal business administration and analysis. 

We will not rent, trade or sell your data to others. 

If you have opted to receive Wikivorce communications, we will use your personal information to send these newsletters to you. 

If you have requested to be kept informed of services that we offer, we will contact you with these details. 

You may receive emails to notify you that you have a message in your Wikivorce inbox, or to let you know that someone has replied to your forum posting. 

We will respect your email privacy. You will not receive unsolicited mail from Wikivorce and/or from third parties. We will, however, mail you occasionally with information about important changes to our service. 

We monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage in order to help us develop the design and layout of the website. 

For these purposes we may transfer, store and process your personal information internationally, including to/in countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA). Other countries offer differing levels of protection for personal information, not all of which will be as high as the levels of protection offered in the UK. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. 

## Cookie Policy

We use cookies and similar tools across our websites to improve their performance and enhance your user experience. This policy explains how we do that.

#### What are cookies?

Cookies are small text files which a website may put on your computer or mobile device when you first visit a site or page. The cookie will help the website, or another website, to recognise your device the next time you visit. Web beacons or other similar files can also do the same thing. We use the term “cookies” in this policy to refer to all files that collect information in this way.

There are many functions cookies serve. For example, they can help us to remember your username and preferences, analyse how well our website is performing, or even allow us to recommend content we believe will be most relevant to you.

Certain cookies contain personal information – for example, if you click to “remember me” when logging in, a cookie will store your username. Most cookies won’t collect information that identifies you, and will instead collect more general information such as how users arrive at and use our websites, or a user’s general location.

#### What sort of cookies does Wikivorce use?

Generally, our cookies perform up to four different functions:

1\. _Essential cookies_

Some cookies are essential for the operation of our website. For example, some cookies store the contents of a customer's shopping basket during the ordering process. If a user opts to disable these cookies, the user will not be able to access our services.

2. _Performance Cookies_

We utilise other cookies to analyse how our visitors use our websites and to monitor website performance. This allows us to provide a high quality experience by customising our offering and quickly identifying and fixing any issues that arise. For example, we might use performance cookies to keep track of which pages are most popular, which method of linking between pages is most effective, and to determine why some pages are receiving error messages. 

3. _Functionality Cookies_

We use functionality cookies to allow us to remember your preferences. For example, cookies save you the trouble of typing in your username every time you access the site. 

4\. _Advertising Cookies_

Wikivorce and our advertisers use cookies to serve you with advertisements that we believe are relevant to you and your interests. For example, if you read a number of articles on motoring on Wikivorce or on other sites, a car manufacturer might infer you are interested in this topic and serve you with its car advertisements. You might see these advertisements on Wikivorce and on other sites that you visit. However, we do not tell our advertisers who you are.

#### Does anyone else use cookies on Wikivorce websites?

Advertisers sometimes use their own cookies to provide you with targeted advertising. For example, advertisers may use a profile they have built on sites that you have previously visited to present you with more relevant advertisements during your visit to Wikivorce.com. We believe that it is useful to our users to see advertisements that are more relevant to their interests. If you are based in the European Union and would like to learn more about how advertisers use these types of cookies or to choose not to receive them, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). If you are based in the United States and would like to learn more, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

We also use or allow third parties to serve cookies that fall into the four categories above. For example, like many companies, we use Google Analytics to help us monitor our website traffic. We may also use third party cookies to help us with market research, revenue tracking, improving site functionality and monitoring compliance with our terms and conditions and copyright policy. 

#### Can a website user block cookies?

As we’ve explained above, cookies help you to get the most out of our websites. 

The first time you accessed our website after 25 May 2012, you should have seen an overlay which explained that by continuing to access our site, you are consenting to our use of cookies.

However, if you do wish to disable our cookies then please follow the instructions on How to Manage Cookies below.

Please remember that if you do choose to disable cookies, you may find that certain sections of our website do not work properly.

If, having been told that our site uses cookies, and having been directed to our Cookie policy, and having been directed to information on How to Disable Cookies, you continue to browse our website without disabling cookies then we will assume your implied consent to use cookies.

#### More Information

More detail on how businesses use cookies is available at [www.allaboutcookies.org.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org./)

If you have any queries regarding this Cookie Policy please contact our Privacy Officer by e-mail at privacy@wikivorce.com.

## How to Manage Cookies

As we explain in our Cookie Policy (above), cookies help you to get the most out of our websites. 

If you do disable our cookies you may find that certain sections of our website do not work. For example, you may have difficulties logging in or viewing articles.

How to disable behaviourally targeted advertising cookies

If you are concerned about behaviourally targeted advertising cookies (which serve you advertisements based on your use of Wikivorce.com and other websites), users based in the European Union can visit [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) and users based in the US can visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> to opt out of these third party cookies.

The above websites are not Wikivorce sites and we are not responsible for their content.

#### How to enable and disable cookies using your browser

_Google Chrome_

  * Click on the ‘wrench’ icon on the browser (usually found top-right corner) to open the tools menu
  * From the tools menu select ‘Options’ 
  * Click the ‘Under the Hood’ tab from the menu on the left.
  * In the ‘Privacy’ section, select the ‘Content settings’ button
  * To enable cookies: select ‘Allow local data to be set’ option 
  * To disable cookies: select ‘Block all cookies’ option
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Chrome. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Chrome, refer to the following page from Google: [http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=95647](http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=95647)

_Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.0, 7.0, 8.0_

  * Click on 'Tools' at the top of your browser window and select 'Internet Options'
  * In the options window navigate to the 'Privacy' tab
  * To enable cookies: Set the slider to ‘Medium’ or below
  * To disable cookies: Move the slider to the top to block all cookies 
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Explorer. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Internet Explorer, refer to the following page from Microsoft: <http://windows.microsoft.com/en-GB/windows-vista/Block-or-allow-cookies>

_Mozilla Firefox_

  * Click on 'Tools' at the browser menu and select ‘Options’
  * Select the Privacy panel
  * To enable cookies: Check ‘Accept cookies for sites’
  * To disable cookies: Uncheck at ‘Accept cookies for sites’ 
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Firefox. For more information, refer to the following page from Mozilla: <http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/Enabling%20and%20disabling%20cookies>

_Opera_

  * Click on 'Setting’ at the browser menu and select 'Settings'
  * Select ‘Quick Preferences’ 
  * To enable cookies: check “Enable Cookies”
  * To disable cookies: uncheck “Enable Cookies”
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Opera. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Opera, refer to the following page from Opera Software: <http://www.opera.com/browser/tutorials/security/privacy/>

_Safari on OSX_

  * Click on 'Safari'  at the menu bar and select the 'Preferences' option
  * Click on 'Security'
  * To enable cookies: In the 'Accept cookies' section select 'Only from site you navigate to'
  * To disable cookies: In the ‘Accept cookies’ section select ‘Never’
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Safari. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Safari, refer to the following page from Apple:  <http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?path=Safari/3.0/en/9277.html>

_All other browsers_

Please look for a “help” function in the browser or contact the browser provider.
